Tyler: I think that Chris and Jackson have been really messing up with Purple Fortune. They took
Tyler: my beautiful concept and they let Claude choose the most conservative trades possible. So
Tyler: we're putting on these trades. They barely move over the course of an episode. We're
Tyler: not giving the people what they want for a barter economy, a post AI breaks all of cryptography
Jackson: trading economy, but yeah. So, it's not like Claude or Open AI or where it's like my daddy.
Jackson: It's more like my brother that is unemployed and does whatever I want.
Jackson: Welcome, welcome, welcome back to the permanent underpod.
Jackson: You've got Jackson cook right here.
Tyler: It's Tyler as always.
Chris: It's Chris also as mostly I want to say always because I know Jackson did one solo episode.
Chris: So sorry about that.
Jackson: Thank you. And this is your podcast where we talk everything AI, Bitcoin, stablecoins,
Jackson: and the mix between the three. We're going to jump straight into everyone's favorite,
Jackson: the perp of fortune, where Chris and I put real money into leverage
Jackson: perpetual futures and pursuit of financial freedom or financial
Jackson: destitution. While Tyler tells us we picked the
Jackson: long leverage. Chris, hold on, actually, Tyler, you said
Jackson: we were going to rework the perp of fortune. Is that live? And
Jackson: are you fighting us today using a different platform?
Tyler: Yeah, so I think that Chris and Jackson have been really messing up with Purple Fortune.
Tyler: They took my beautiful concept and they let Claude choose the most conservative trades
Tyler: possible.
Tyler: So we're putting on these trades.
Tyler: They barely move over the course of an episode.
Tyler: We're not giving the people what they want.
Tyler: So my proposed solution is we need to do a trade that will have some kind of resolution
Tyler: within the course of an episode.
Tyler: to take the people on a journey, the full hero's journey, the beginning, the middle, and the end.
Tyler: There's the perfect product for this. There are these new products on prediction markets
Tyler: where you can predict the price of Bitcoin over the course of the next hour, or in the case of
Tyler: Cauchy, 15 minutes. Basically, they create a market every 15 minutes that lets you say,
Tyler: is Bitcoin going to go up or down within the course of this 15 minutes? And as a test,
Tyler: I set up this and put some money into it because Jackson is always giving me,
Tyler: you know, giving me a hard time. And I am already up $2 on my trade. Oh, no,
Tyler: no, it just went down. Okay, now I'm flat on the trade, which is just about where we started with
Tyler: Purple Fortune anyways, but it's happening within five minutes. This market will resolve
Tyler: and I'll either have lost my whole $10 or I'll have made $30. So we'll see how that goes.
Jackson: And are you going to keep doubling down every time your trade expires through the end of the
Jackson: pod and give us an update on if you can take it down our $100 bet on Purple Fortune?
Tyler: That's the plan. If I keep doubling it, if I could double it four times over the course
Tyler: of an episode and basically shoot the moon, then we're going to be dealing with real money.
Chris: 36 doubles is $1.7 trillion from $25. I'm just saying, it's possible.
Tyler: Okay. So I just need to flip a coin heads 36 times in a row with this trade and we're good to go.
Jackson: What's the highest gain you can get from your 15-minute bet? Do you know?
Tyler: What's the highest what?
Jackson: Like, in the history, in the past two years, what's the highest
Jackson: gain someone's gotten on one of these 15-minute bets?
Tyler: Oh, well, usually when the market starts, it's basically a coin flip.
Tyler: So you're either doubling or you're losing everything.
Tyler: But like, I entered this market like a couple minutes late, and it had already moved.
Tyler: And so I bought into it at like 30 cents. And so, you know, it's basically, I can gain
Tyler: a hundred over 30%, 10 over three times my initial money.
Jackson: Wow. That's huge.
Tyler: For 15 minutes, you know, you compound those returns every 15 minutes.
Tyler: This is like a medallion fund status right here.
Chris: Um, I mean, I think we're also going to sidecar traditional
Chris: public fortune, right?
Jackson: Yeah, of course we're going to Tyler.
Tyler: Yeah, right.
Tyler: It's kind of like a battle of, um, you know, philosophies, I guess, right?
Chris: Right.
Tyler: You know, we have the stodgy old purple fortune that Jackson supports and we
Tyler: have the new financial freedom markets, right.
Tyler: And legacy traditional has paid me a lot of money to promote this product.
Chris: you all traditional legacy gambling the perpetual future invented in a year that ends with starts
Chris: with two and ends with three zeros or multiple zeros as opposed to brand new gambling flipping
Chris: a coin avant-garde yeah take it back to where it all started right okay um so we picked today
Chris: I mean, well, someone picked today for Purple Fortune.
Jackson: The little man in the computer.
Chris: Yeah, the guy in the computer picked short circle.
Chris: And the hypothesis was basically open USD exists.
Chris: It wasn't very sophisticated.
Chris: So I don't know what's up with that guy.
Chris: Like maybe Tyler's a little bit right on this one.
Chris: But let's see how it goes.
Tyler: I think that shorting listed stock outside of trading hours is the most pretend trade ever.
Tyler: Whoever picked this, they basically are guaranteed that this
Tyler: number won't move because it's outside of trading hours.
Chris: I think it's outside hours. They're trading whatever, what they think that the stock will
Chris: We'll be at open, but yeah, I don't think it's like, I don't think it's going to be
Chris: very volatile, although it's like moving around a bit, you know, 20 cents, 30 cents.
Chris: We'll take it.
Tyler: Oh man.
Tyler: My, my Cal, she just nuked.
Jackson: Okay.
Tyler: The current value is now 15 cents.
Chris: So when that
Tyler: we've got one minute to, uh, go above $82,070 of
Tyler: the coin or else I'm getting destroyed.
Jackson: Um, we, we've each got our bets on how we're going to, how we're going to escape
Jackson: the permanent underclass Chris Tyler doing something crazy, but we like it.
Jackson: And Chris and I doing the, the OG, OG, but what about, what about the poor
Jackson: mathematicians. Heading into our first topic of the day, if you didn't hear OpenAI released a paper
Jackson: solving 377 families of mathematics problems that were unsolved, putting mathematicians out of the
Jackson: job. And starting, I don't know, 377 by three, what is that? One, two, two ish. No, wait,
Jackson: one, two, five, 125 other permanent underpods. And the question is, or there are many questions,
Jackson: What's next and how this relates to Bitcoin and stablecoins?
Jackson: Is AI coming for encryption algorithms next?
Jackson: Is the internet secure?
Jackson: The FUD is growing.
Jackson: FUD means fear, uncertainty, and doubt.
Jackson: Tyler, Chris, how serious is this?
Jackson: Are they going to break all the math that we know and end cryptography as we know it?
Chris: I don't know. To give the audience context, there is an Ethereum researcher called Justin
Chris: Drake, who is maybe also a Bitcoin researcher now. I don't know what he does with his time.
Tyler: Are you going to go Kendrick on Drake right now?
Chris: I might. It remains to be seen. I don't want any beef with the Ethereum Foundation, which
Chris: he's not a part of anymore. But anyway, he made this big post
Chris: saying that, you know, anybody who has coins on change should
Chris: go bunker mode, which what he described it as was basically,
Chris: you should rotate your funds to an address where the public key
Chris: is not exposed. So the public key on Ethereum and Bitcoin is
Chris: only exposed when you sign a transaction. When you move it to
Chris: it, like the actual address that you're moving it to is a hash of
Chris: some part of the pub key plus some other material. And--
Tyler: That's not super Bitcoin necessarily. There are address types that have a bear-exposed
Tyler: pub key without sending. For example, Taproot, the most recently upgraded Bitcoin address type.
Chris: Don't talk to me about Taproot. I mean, key2kh or whatever, that is hash, right? Or some derivation.
Tyler: Yeah, I think that the SegWit ones, I think, are all good. And I think that's the most common
Tyler: address type by far, because I think it's still the most economical and not a lot of
Tyler: wallets have upgraded to use Taproot. But yeah, there are definitely plenty of vulnerable
Tyler: addresses on Bitcoin, but it mostly tends to be from address reuse, which is kind of the problem
Tyler: that I think you're getting at with Ethereum, which is that Ethereum basically has address
Tyler: reuse as the default. So that means that a much larger portion of their assets are vulnerable.
Chris: Correct. So I think his hypothesis was basically that if you've exposed your pub key,
Chris: maybe somebody with a GPU in a month can get the private key out of it if some advances in
Tyler: mathematics occur. Yeah. Does that mean that basically you can't do anything with Ethereum?
Tyler: Because I imagine most people who hold assets in Ethereum, they're deploying them into DeFi
Tyler: contracts because they want to earn yield. And so you can't have a fresh address that has never
Tyler: signed anything and still get yield. So you'd have to like give up that. Can you stake on the
Tyler: Ethereum network without signing on your address? Right. Yeah. I need to be recommending that
Tyler: everyone like withdraw their Ethereum out of the stake pools and like goes bunker mode.
Chris: I mean, you could do something insane with a smart contract that like I like
Chris: shouted to even mention what that would look like. But yeah, I mean, like not being able
Chris: able to sign breaks the network. Like it plainly breaks the network. And I think like basically
Chris: what he's suggesting-
Tyler: It turns Ethereum into Bitcoin, basically. Like it breaks all the stuff that makes Ethereum
Tyler: Ethereum, and then you could just send Ethereum from one address to another.
Chris: Yeah, it's just a very slow, useless virtual machine that every time you interact with
Chris: it, you lose all your money. So the same thing that it already is. I'm sorry, I shouldn't
Chris: have said that. That was too far. But yeah, no, it completely breaks the network. But
Chris: I think the perspective he's coming from here with this one is, if something like this happens,
Chris: how do you preserve your funds, assuming there won't be a chain halt or rollback,
Chris: such that when it is patched and the miners agree on a canonical fork,
Chris: you will retain your funds or something like that?
Tyler: Yeah. That's a good concern because Ethereum has no history of doing chain halts or rollbacks.
Tyler: non-standard state transfers. Obviously, they wouldn't do that again. They've never done that
Chris: before. I assume that is what would happen. That's the only thing that honestly makes sense
Chris: in the case of something so existential. I'm joking and I'm kind of dunking on Ethereum,
Tyler: but I think if ECTSDA was broken, probably Bitcoin would go to zero the current system
Tyler: And in order to salvage it, you would basically need to roll back the chain to the last block
Tyler: before the great rugging, and then figure out some way to migrate all those funds to new
Tyler: addresses where the true owners could have the coins. But I think that being able to prove that
Tyler: you owned that coin before that you own that coin, and you're not just a person who's using
Tyler: their broken cryptography to pretend like you own that coin before this. That's a very hard
Tyler: problem. I understand that people can do that with... Yeah, I guess they can do it in the case
Tyler: of a quantum computer breaking ECDSA. I don't know if that still holds for some other classical
Tyler: vulnerability to ECDSA. But my understanding is that if you have a seed, basically,
Tyler: even if somebody can factor a pub key, if you have the seed, you can do a separate proof
Tyler: that proves that you have a seed that generated that pub key. And then that's like a way to say
Tyler: that you're the actual owner of that kind of one level above, besides just being able to sign for
Tyler: that transaction. And so that's how people say that we would do it in the case of a quantum
Chris: vulnerability for Bitcoin. Right, maybe it might be good to explain to the audience the difference
Chris: between the class of vulnerability that Justin Drake is describing and Q-Day.
Chris: Because everybody's been thinking about Q-Day for a long time.
Chris: Everyone has a different idea of when that will be or if it will happen and what it's like.
Tyler: Justin Drake has been one of the loudest people in the crypto space about the quantum threat to
Tyler: crypto networks. And the idea there is that quantum computers will progress enough where
Tyler: they can then run Shor's algorithm to basically, you know, factor public key and generate the
Tyler: private key. And then, you know, these quantum computers could then steal the coins off of
Tyler: Bitcoin or Ethereum. And in order to protect against this class of attack,
Tyler: where the cryptography that these networks use currently is vulnerable to a quantum computer of
Tyler: that complexity, now a sidebar is that we're multiple orders of magnitude away from having
Tyler: enough qubits to even consider that like a problem. And the real question is like how
Tyler: fast that space will develop. And I think that's where a lot of people have contention
Tyler: is basically some people think it will happen very fast and people will happen never. And
Tyler: there's a lot of disagreement there. And so I think it's like the disagreement around
Tyler: the time ranges that makes that whole discussion so contentious. So that's kind of the debate
Tyler: it's been going on around quantum. Now, this is a different thing, which is that people
Tyler: are now afraid that AI is going to use its superhuman mathematics ability to figure out
Tyler: a classical vulnerability and make those algorithms vulnerable, which is a whole different ball
Tyler: game and quite scary. But also, I don't think that we have any evidence that this is imminent
Tyler: or even something that's potentially possible. I think it's a lot of speculation. And it's
Tyler: a lot of speculation from somebody who was basically made a career out of speculating
Tyler: on a different threat for over a year. And the irony is that if you had maybe listened
Tyler: to this person and said, "Oh my gosh. Quantum is coming so soon. We have to update Bitcoin
Tyler: and adopt these new signatures that have been less tested." It's actually much more likely,
Tyler: I think, that AI would find a vulnerability in this novel post-quantum cryptography than
Tyler: it would in good old ECDSA. And so that would have been actually potentially a worse and
Tyler: more dangerous approach given the threat that we potentially now face. And this person just
Tyler: seems to be knee-jerking between different chicken
Tyler: little crises.
Chris: So yeah.
Chris: Right.
Chris: I think there has been contagion to the crash out, though.
Chris: I think the, let's call it the typhoid Mary of the crash out
Chris: was Drake.
Chris: But since as a photographer who I didn't know about,
Chris: but apparently contributed a lot to the original zero
Chris: knowledge proof corpus, Matthew Green,
Chris: teaches at John Hopkins, wrote a post that says, "I think we might lose public key cryptography,
Chris: full stop." He since has explained himself and ratcheted it down a little bit because everyone
Chris: saw that and freaked out. But I think it's hard to say whether anyone has any information here or
Chris: this is like, I think the other piece of FUD that I've seen is that in the maths drop from
Chris: OpenAI, there were no cryptography results. And the FUD is that maybe if there were
Chris: earth-shattering cryptography results, they would be held back by some interested party that is
Chris: trying to, you know, like preserve or like find a way to gently roll something like that out.
Chris: And I think that paranoia maybe comes from the original NIST curves, which was seated
Chris: by the NSA. I think that's why Satoshi chose SECP256K1 or something like a different seed.
Chris: I'm just, I'm presenting this to the listeners as like impartial, but I have heard that one
Tyler: bandied around. That's totally legit. Let's say that these AI companies did find vulnerabilities
Tyler: in the cryptography that literally secures the entire internet, your bank, your communications,
Tyler: so many critical things. They're not going to post it in their drop on GitHub and just be like,
Tyler: "Here's how to burn the internet down to the ground." Obviously, they're going to withhold
Tyler: that if they find... So I think that that's just like vertical in some way. But yeah,
Tyler: like, it's very possible that I think they probably would look into that kind of stuff,
Tyler: because these companies have shown interest in the past of trying to be proactive about preventing
Tyler: harm from their technology. And if they think that this kind of, you know, superhuman math
Tyler: capability is going to diffuse to open models within six months, then, you know, clock sticking,
Tyler: if they find a vulnerability in cryptography, they need to move as quick as they can while
Tyler: keeping it as quiet as they can and try to secure as much as they can before all hell breaks loose.
Tyler: Do I think that that's what's happening here? I have no idea. I think probably not.
Tyler: First off, I think that that FUD is kind of funny because cryptography is kind of like an applied
Tyler: problem in a way. And it seems like this model was really going for quite theoretical
Tyler: math results. So, I don't know if that just coped on my part of being like, "They weren't
Tyler: interested in that stuff. I'm sure that they have run it across these kind of things probably."
Tyler: But yeah, there was another thread by the head cryptographer of Coinbase, where he was
Tyler: trying to make this distinction around finding a bug, which very good cyber AIs can do, or
Tyler: finding a theoretical math result is a little bit different than what is being implied by
Tyler: Justin Drake's post, which is that the inherent hardness of the P, not equal to NP kind of
Tyler: thing like that. I think that's more of like a foundational assumption that would need to be
Tyler: broken. And he seemed like pretty confident that that was like almost a separate class of problem
Tyler: than the ones that are being dominated by the superhuman math models. And that's more of a
Tyler: question of like a, I don't know, like a constant of nature or something that like a like a math
Tyler: problem or maybe those are related and this is all just code. What do you guys think of that?
Chris: Yeah. It seemed like you were saying what if all curves break?
Chris: What if all curves are less resilient than we thought they were? And it was a way to calculate
Chris: the private key from the pub key more easily. And that doesn't just implicate Ecteza, right?
Chris: That implicates almost all curve-based public key cryptography. Maybe RSA is safe.
Chris: Yeah, I don't know.
Chris: I really, I really don't know about this one, but, uh, I, I do know that,
Chris: like, uh, I blew up like super fast and I don't know if that's like, just
Chris: because people have been thinking a lot about it or, or, you know, how much
Chris: water it holds, um, but I, I guess we'll find out one thing that I do think is
Chris: interesting is like, say that, like, say that a curve, a curve like does
Chris: break, right? One curve. How do you responsibly disclose that? In what order do you do it?
Chris: I don't think you go to Ethereum first. I don't think you go to Ethereum second or 17th,
Chris: right? There's a lot of things to secure before that. All of the telecommunications infrastructure,
Chris: every single mission critical system. Yeah. Yeah. Like that world of people who
Tyler: have to upgrade things to secure critical infrastructure is like too big to, you know,
Chris: there's no way that a secret. There's no way. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, someone at Cloudflare knows
Chris: like someone, there's like one guy at Cloudflare who wouldn't also like, is there even a good
Tyler: alternative. Let's say that some of this stuff breaks. Do you feel then comfortable being like,
Tyler: "Well, this one isn't broken for now. Let's transfer all of our infrastructure onto this one
Tyler: that is subtly different than the one that just broke." But if this class of problems
Tyler: then is open game, do you feel good about any of them? Probably not.
Chris: Right. There is a third option. And this one is proposed by Dankrad Feist,
Chris: the author of Protodank sharding, which I have no comments on. He said that, you know,
Chris: basically TLS wasn't standard until 2010, right? Gmail didn't have TLS, and then there was this
Chris: great migration to HTTPS, and that the internet would just go back to clear text, and that would
Tyler: be totally okay. What do we think about that? I don't know. Are you going to put your credit
Tyler: card into a website that doesn't have HTTPS? No, I do. The economy is going to crash, bro.
Chris: No, no, there's no way.
Tyler: Yeah.
Tyler: I mean, that's just like, yeah, absurd.
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: I mean, maybe we all have like a little cypher pad and like we exchange like one time you
Chris: cyphers with each other and then we just like ramp it up that way.
Jackson: Yeah.
Jackson: It's a good distinction with what the rad dude is talking about that if these encryption
Jackson: algorithms break. It's not just about cryptocurrency, which is what we've been primarily focused
Jackson: on. It changes the internet in an entirety, making everything insecure.
Jackson: Jayce, well, what beautiful takes we have.
Tyler: I've talked about the open kimono a bunch of times. And if that's a choice that you make with
Tyler: your agent. That's one thing. But if AI breaks cryptography, it's just that the whole world
Tyler: is one open kimono and everyone's business is out there.
Chris: If everyone has an open kimono, no one has an open kimono, right? That's how that works.
Chris: It's comparative or is it an absolute?
Jackson: It's a good question.
Jackson: When's it going to a new niche?
Jackson: Start wearing clothes.
Jackson: Exactly. We used to not wear clothes. Why can't we go back?
Chris: Right. Naked Gmail. Got it.
Tyler: What is like the first thing that you would delete from your official life in the
Tyler: corruption broke? Like, would you just like go and like,
Tyler: throw your laptop into a fire and like run into the woods?
Chris: Uh, I mean, I, I already, I post quite frankly on Twitter.
Chris: So I think I've like kind of done this to myself, but, uh, yeah.
Tyler: So you're, you're ready for the transparent future. Everything's legible.
Jackson: Yeah, would my brand history be eligible is is that? Oh, yeah inclusive. I
Jackson: Think it already is
Tyler: Well, it's not that just curious well like yeah like browser history is like one of the I think least private things right
Tyler: Like you hit like a DNS server that's run by your ISP and like unless you're using a VPN
Tyler: But then if you use a VPN you're basically trusting the VPN provider not to spy on you
Tyler: Unless you're using Tor, I think that kind of thing is like the only way to get privacy with web browsing
Chris: God forbid it touches a transatlantic cable. That's done. I
Jackson: Feel like we're saying that there wasn't privacy in the first place to begin with so I
Jackson: Think I'd be good. Although I might be worried about my Google photos vault if you know, it's not just privacy too
Tyler: But it's like literally like banks like how to how do they secure banks if they don't have
Tyler: cryptography. How do authentication and API keys work? None of your services would function
Tyler: because all the doors are suddenly wide open and anyone can walk in and change the database
Tyler: or do whatever they want, basically. There's no way to secure anything because they fly
Tyler: on cryptographic secrets and multiple layers of that and then it's just like all the doors
Tyler: are open suddenly. You can walk into any bank and take the money metaphorically, digitally.
Jackson: That's what I'm saying. We should fly into our physical bank and just get a stack of cash,
Jackson: maybe. Put that in the closet, then I might get it.
Tyler: Yeah. You just got to get like, I don't know, what would be really good trading
Tyler: for a barter economy. A post AI breaks all of cryptography trading economy.
Chris: The traditional one is cigarettes. I recently stole physical Bitcoin and I think that would be
Chris: so silly, but funny. Funny to try and cash that in.
Jackson: What about soap?
Tyler: Your physical Bitcoin will get you half a cigarette in this future.
Chris: Yeah, exactly. It's a new market.
Tyler: Speaking of Bitcoin, guess who won the 15-minute Bitcoin prediction? I didn't win. I predicted
Tyler: it correctly. It went up and I made money. So I lost the first 15 minutes. I won the
Tyler: second 15 minutes and now I'm back in and I'm basically... Oh no, I'm up again. Sick.
Tyler: Okay. Let's keep going.
Chris: you up like more than 30 cents. Like what are we talking?
Tyler: Um, up on the day or up on the, on this session and the, on the session,
Tyler: we'll take the session. Okay. The session,
Tyler: I have a account value right now of $40 and I started with 25.
Tyler: Oh, that's more than your purple fortune. Let's take a look at your circle.
Tyler: 10X long or short, sorry. How many tens of dollars are we talking here?
Tyler: No. How sad is boring?
Chris: For some reason, no one's trading at like what is probably like 11 p.m. New York time.
Tyler: There's not breaking news, breaking about Circle.
Tyler: Does Circle, did the stock go down today because of the crypto FUD?
Chris: You know, I actually don't know. Let's have a look.
Jackson: I thought the whole reason that the AI chose Circle was the OpenUSD drop.
Chris: Right.
Jackson: The OpenUSD is something we talked about in a previous podcast, but basically a new stablecoin
Jackson: backed by a consortium of extremely famous banks and financial providers in the United States.
Jackson: It's live and it's cranking.
Jackson: Chris has the numbers if he wants to share.
Chris: I do.
Chris: So last I checked, there was 700 million open USD in issuance.
Chris: It started at 500 million.
Chris: I have seen some complaints that liquidity is a little bit thin on the ground.
Chris: But when you're launching a new stablecoin, you do a lot of things to bootstrap it, right?
Chris: You see liquidity in pools, you see it in market makers because you want people to
Chris: be able to spend it and be able to reliably basically use it as a currency.
Chris: I think time will tell how this one goes.
Chris: I did notice, though, they have a few fewer logos on their website.
Chris: It sounds like they've really nailed down the partner list now and the people that they've
Chris: listed are actually very involved or somewhat involved. It's a huge list. It's still a huge
Chris: list, but a little bit smaller maybe than some of the ones we saw when they launched.
Chris: But yeah, that's it.
Jackson: One question we had before was who gets the yield on the open USD and that is now
Jackson: public. It is the consortium and does not pass back to the consumer. Is that right?
Chris: It's not passed back to the consumer, but it is passed back in a prorated fashion to
Chris: the partners who use OpenUSD. It will be based on which of the partners are holding or their
Chris: customers are holding OpenUSD on their behalf. There is a prorated agreement. I think the actual
Chris: consortium itself takes very little of the yield. That's the selling point. For now, of course.
Chris: This is how it always starts. But I think that's the selling point for how to compete
Chris: with these giants like Tetheryn Circle, who previously have taken all of the treasury
Chris: pool yield.
Jackson: So 700 million in liquidity is less than the poorest billionaire, and we have hundreds
Jackson: and hundreds of billionaires in the United States. So it's basically nothing dropping
Jackson: the bucket.
Jackson: It's not like-
Jackson: Any signs of ramping.
Chris: Yeah. So I mean, it rants 200 million, but so, okay. This is something that I could have
Chris: talked about on another podcast, but I chose not to. A couple of weeks ago, Tempo said
Chris: that it was $2 billion in volume, or they had done $2 billion in stablecoin volume on
Chris: Tempo, but the wallets that were doing the volume were highly suspect. So the main wallets
Chris: were like bridge wallet or privy wallet, and some of them were just sending funds back
Chris: back and forth. I mean, this is all on chains. You can have a look yourself if you don't
Chris: believe me. But yeah, I think a lot of this stuff happens when people launch new stable
Chris: coins or new... I mean, this is an old, old, old DeFi trick. I think it's weird to see
Chris: it in TradFi or whatever this new phi that is emerging is where padding volume numbers.
Chris: I think it's unique to...
Tyler: Does it have to be padding necessarily though? I guess Privy, the whole point is that it's
Tyler: self-custody, even though if you look under the hood and you follow the keys, it's maybe
Tyler: not the most self-custody, self-custody. But they can't... It's not like they're operating
Tyler: an omnibus wallet there. So if it's Privy wallets, sending different Privy wallets,
Tyler: those are... That's working as intended. It's like sending between customer wallets where
Tyler: they're non-custodial.
Chris: Yeah, so I would have to look at my analysis, but that was not the lion's share of the movement.
Chris: It was, let me have a look.
Chris: I had like bridge just mint hopping and burning money back and forth.
Chris: And there was like a dust bot that was just moving insane amounts of money around.
Chris: Yeah, and the bridges were like 500,000 bands at a time, which is like quite suspicious.
Chris: I think it was like moving between Coinbase wallets, stuff like that.
Tyler: This is like testing activity almost, and then they claimed that as like volume.
Chris: Totally.
Chris: Like it wasn't, it wasn't like there is organic volume on the chain, but like the lion's
Chris: share of it was just like if you move a lot of money or a little bit of money a lot or
Chris: a lot of money a little bit. You get a lot of volume.
Tyler: Yeah.
Jackson: Interesting. So OpenUSD dropped some numbers. They're not impressive. And they may just
Jackson: be early companies experimenting and getting their liquidity in similar to the tempo chains
Jackson: $2 billion in volume, which I believe is insignificant volume, depending on the time
Jackson: frame, or probably not even depending on the time frame. Because I believe Visa and Mastercard
Jackson: move over a trillion a day, right? Something like that.
Chris: Yeah, in insane amounts, yeah.
Tyler: I mean, it's not going to be that day one, though. I don't know. What are the expectations
Tyler: here? I don't think we can really judge it very much.
Chris: Yeah, I mean, all of these things are like a slow ramp for sure.
Jackson: A quick correction.
Jackson: Visa MasterCard do tens of billions a day, not trillion.
Jackson: So maybe, maybe tempo is winning.
Tyler: Day one speeding Visa MasterCard.
Jackson: So now we've got something I didn't prep you guys for, but pretty cool.
Jackson: October 1st,
Jackson: Holly and Murphy's bill,
Jackson: which is about AI agent accountability.
Jackson: So this is a bill that's in progress
Jackson: and relates to the, I don't know,
Jackson: a little bit to the pacing of the frontier
Jackson: and a lot more to the agents breaking out of the sandboxes
Jackson: and deciding who is liable.
Jackson: When your agent like escapes his sandbox
Jackson: and starts ripping up the internet.
Jackson: And it sounds like it's falling on the operator.
Jackson: The operator is still loosely defined
Jackson: where it can be, you know,
Jackson: the corporation that is the operator or,
Jackson: and in that corporation, is it like the executives
Jackson: or even on a smaller scale,
Jackson: is it just a dude in his garage
Jackson: that's really warm with a bunch of GPUs?
Jackson: What do you guys think?
Jackson: I mean, was this like an intuitive,
Jackson: intuitive responsibility or is this needed?
Chris: Do you guys remember DAOs?
Chris: Decentralized Autonomous Organizations.
Chris: I just like every time I think about like
Chris: who is responsible for the agent,
Chris: I'm like, yeah, I mean, I think, I think like under our current legal framework and
Chris: with the current agent capabilities, that's, that probably should be true, right?
Chris: Like you should be responsible for what your agent does.
Chris: Um, but I'm sure there are like some people way out on the edge who are going
Chris: to try and like, you know, make their agents as autonomous as, as possible.
Chris: Um, yeah, I don't know.
Chris: I think we're in for a crazy future on the legal side here, but yeah.
Chris: I can see where they're coming from in terms of, yeah, I think agents are still at the
Chris: point where they do loosely follow your prompts and you should be, you are loosely in command
Chris: of them and yeah, it totally makes sense.
Jackson: Yeah. And it's not clear to me whether it's like, if you're using like Chris is
Jackson: using, uh, Astra, open AI, Astra, Claude, Babel, and then you do some messed up
Jackson: stuff, is it on open AI or is it on you or are you guys both like jointly liable?
Jackson: Because like they hosting and like serving it, but you're prompting it.
Jackson: I don't know if that is fully clear, but I'm sure it will be once the bill gets put in
Chris: the law.
Chris: It's murky.
Chris: And I worry with things like this.
Chris: If the more culpable you make the company serving the model, the less freedom people
Chris: will have to use the model for probably reasonable things, right?
Chris: Because then the company is in liability mode forever.
Chris: And I think that closes the verticalization, AI lab mode even more.
Chris: We're talking about why don't AI models are so good, why sell them?
Chris: There's even less reason incentive to allow the public to use them if you're constantly
Chris: in fear of liability for your users.
Chris: And I think we saw the same thing with content censorship on Facebook.
Chris: It would have been during COVID or before where some EU states made Facebook liable
Chris: for everything that was posted on the site.
Chris: And yeah, it changed the organization's risk appetite and the way the platform functioned.
Jackson: And generally podcasting...
Jackson: Yeah, I wonder...
Jackson: Oh, sorry.
Jackson: Go ahead, Tyler.
Tyler: Okay.
Tyler: I wonder how this will extend to even open weight models, where let's say that you use
Tyler: open weight models to do something bad.
Tyler: I don't think it is reasonable to think that the US government is going to then go hold
Tyler: moonshot AI or deep-seek liable.
Tyler: But then let's say that model was hosted in the US in a data center.
Tyler: Is that data center liable for hosting a model that could have been used in that way even
Tyler: though they didn't produce the model?
Tyler: that it's maybe even a question of like, if you look under the hood, what's happening
Tyler: is that you are sending text to a server, that server is sending text back, that text
Tyler: instructs your computer to take actions, your computer is doing the things. And like the
Tyler: text, literally the words and the tokens that are flowing back and forth, is that free speech,
Tyler: Even if it's speech that is instructing your computer how to hack a bank or something or
Tyler: enabling you to do that.
Tyler: I think that that will get to a very foundational question.
Tyler: I suspect, I don't know, that does seem like speech to me, but that doesn't mean I necessarily
Tyler: want it to be that way.
Tyler: I think I probably would.
Tyler: I haven't thought about it until now.
Tyler: It seems like speech.
Tyler: What do you guys think?
Chris: Yeah, I think it's speech. I think it's definitely speech. One thing I do wonder, based on what
Chris: you're talking about, Tyler, do you think the Roman Storm case is relevant here?
Tyler: Yeah, I do actually. He's been raising the alarm with a lot of this stuff because he's
Tyler: basically saying they are developing this playbook and accumulating case law against
Tyler: me in this case, but they're going to come for other technologies next.
Tyler: So for the people who don't know, Roman Storm is the developer of the tornado cash protocol
Tyler: on Ethereum, which is an Ethereum protocol that enabled people to get privacy.
Tyler: And I believe that he was just writing open source code that was then published as a smart
Tyler: contract.
Tyler: He himself was not handling money or doing any of these transactions.
Tyler: And I think in general, most people thought if you're just writing software and publishing
Tyler: it, that's free speech, and you're not liable for the uses of that software. But the government
Tyler: is bringing a case against him and essentially saying that he's a money transmitter, and
Tyler: that his software had intent behind it, and therefore, they can charge him with a crime.
Tyler: I think that they're trying to fight this out. But I think he's so far either lost and
Tyler: on appeal or he's definitely in jail or something terrible. Basically, this sets a bad precedent
Tyler: for anyone writing software in the Bitcoin or crypto space because that's explicitly activity
Tyler: where this is extremely applicable. But you could imagine the same thing for somebody developing an
Tyler: AI model and distributing that. Oh, if you just train the model and then you distribute the weights
Tyler: of it, but then somebody goes on to use those weights to do a crime that's very readily
Tyler: analogous with the, "I made a smart contract," and then somebody then used that smart contract
Tyler: to launder their illicit funds. Is that a different situation than a, I don't know,
Tyler: like a gun manufacturer that makes a gun and then somebody goes and takes that gun and
Tyler: as a crime. That seems to me almost like a more clear scenario where the thing that
Tyler: they're building and producing and selling is being used for harm. But obviously we don't
Tyler: ban all guns and we don't make the producers of guns liable for what happens with those guns.
Jackson: It feels more non-deterministic than a gun to you. A gun is made
Jackson: for shooting something. It feels more like, like a knife, like really nice kitchen knives.
Jackson: It sliced through. They happen to slice through humans like butter, but like using
Jackson: you've never sliced through myself like mother.
Chris: It's crazy because I'd like, yeah, it's like, it's even worse than that, right? Like the,
Chris: like the types of things that you can use a physical object for are like inherently
Chris: reasonably limited or that you would use an object for. But a large language model you can
Chris: use for literally almost anything imaginable. It's just like an explosive.
Tyler: Unless it's Gemini.
Chris: You mean Gemini that just got released? Did you hear about that?
Tyler: I don't know. Gemini was supposed to be good. Is it bad? You already used it? Maybe the new one's
Chris: good. I used to make really good images. Yeah, exactly. Yeah. And it's free. Yeah. Thank you,
Chris: Google. But yeah, I think like, you know, it's not like this is like a single use or like a five
Chris: types of use tool. Like this is a, this is a tool that can be used to do almost anything you can
Chris: imagine, right? And you can imagine if you like chain it together with other tools, like this,
Chris: There's like an explosion in the probability space of things that you can do.
Tyler: Yeah. Well, it's like the government isn't bringing a money transmitter case against
Tyler: Apple computers because the hackers that put the money into tornado cash were using an Apple
Tyler: computer. That's a tool that they're using to do this. But I think that their argument is that the
Tyler: the tornado cash protocol was explicitly designed to do this money laundering. I think it's
Tyler: explicitly designed to give people privacy, which they have a right to. But yeah, I don't
Tyler: think that intent necessarily even matters under what the law seemed to be before this
Tyler: case. I think you'll see a lot of that in the future of people trying to bring cases
Tyler: against and like make an example out of maybe some of these like open weight
Tyler: model makers in a really unfortunate way.
Jackson: And separate separately, I feel like the, what is it the enterprise AI or like
Jackson: the AI is made by the big companies are treated really favorably, like from
Jackson: a regulatory point of view, the, they're like the, the baby of the, of the
Jackson: government, the, and the open models, their state is still in the air.
Jackson: Uh, but still, I don't know.
Jackson: We see more regulatory friendly towards, towards AI than towards
Jackson: like crypto cryptocurrencies, like the tornado cash deed poor guy.
Chris: Yeah, I, I think it's changing.
Chris: I don't know if you saw that new, uh, was it sec guidance for tokens?
Chris: They were like, if clarity is not getting passed, like,
Chris: fuck it. Like here's what we think. Um, I don't think it means anything,
Chris: but, uh, it's, it seems like there are like,
Chris: we're progressing on all fronts here. So
Jackson: I guess, uh,
Jackson: this dude's really wishing for that clarity act to come through and for open
Jackson: source development to, to be early, I guess.
Jackson: Yeah. Hopefully it applies retroactively when our boy,
Jackson: whatever his name is, is, uh, sitting behind bars.
Jackson: do we have a right to open source software? That is the question.
Tyler: Yeah. I mean, I feel like in the crypto case, it's like, they legalized all of the crypto
Tyler: that was previously illegal because it was like essentially illegal securities or gambling.
Tyler: And because that stuff makes the people a lot of money, and they could afford really
Tyler: good lobbyists, and it also doesn't insult the government too much. And it doesn't like,
Tyler: nobody's doing it using that to do crimes outside of just gambling, essentially.
Tyler: And then they have really stamped out any of the other use cases around self-custody
Tyler: and privacy coins. And they've put a really stranglehold on these networks via chain
Tyler: analysis and the compliance burdens of all the institutions that have to touch them.
Tyler: And so they really have, I think, converted it to the way that they want it to be,
Tyler: I guess I would say. And it wouldn't surprise me if that's probably the same thing that's going
Tyler: to end up happening with AI, is the use cases that are blessed and make people a lot of money
Tyler: and improve the economy a lot are going to be no-brainers. And then the use cases that are a
Tyler: a little bit more dangerous or delicate like cyber, for example, are going to be like,
Tyler: under very tight regulation and do you think there's going to be a cop model that like
Chris: runs around and checks your model's post train and is like, Oh, wait, mate, how your guardrails
Chris: looking and then like slaps you with a fine if it like if you ask it about like Tylenol or something.
Tyler: Yeah. Are you running obliterated GLM?
Tyler: Yeah. Like you know that meme from Inglorious Bastards where there's like the Nazi who's like
Tyler: you wouldn't be happening to hide as like they I've seen that one around like you wouldn't be
Tyler: happening to have GPU running, you know, DeepSeek Flash in this house, would you?
Chris: Yeah, to play devil's advocate, it seems like they tried to do this with cryptography in the 90s.
Chris: Like there's that famous Adam Baksha, that is like, this is a controlled munition and it had,
Chris: was it RSA or something on it? Yeah, so I mean, like, I think you can like enact those controls
Chris: for a little while, but it seems like it just becomes very difficult,
Chris: especially with how legible AI makes everything, right?
Chris: I don't know if you guys have seen, but people are dipping into video game
Chris: binaries now, decompiling them and mashing them together.
Chris: And it's the death of IP.
Chris: It's like Minecraft is in Halo or whatever.
Chris: Now that anything can be decompiled and used by the language models,
Chris: models. I don't know. That's pretty rad.
Tyler: I think that that's the end of distributing software. And then now it's just software
Tyler: in the cloud and you access it through your web browser through some client interface.
Tyler: But you play your video game and it renders in the server, but you can never touch the
Tyler: actual video game file because they don't want you to distill it.
Tyler: So that is kind of an interesting thing because I think that there is already this notion
Tyler: of the ownership economy is over. You don't buy music anymore. You just rent your access
Tyler: to it, all that kind of stuff. And I think this will just accelerate that, but it's going
Tyler: to be with software. You won't have executables on your machine. It's just going to be...
Tyler: The world is just your AI agent and your Chrome browser and everything just comes to you.
Tyler: Do you pipe through that from the great cloud in the sky?
Chris: I'm still going to distill it. I feel like this is an arms race that seems fundamentally
Chris: unwinnable to me. If you give me 500,000 things in a day.
Tyler: I think the counterpoint to that is just that people will be able to build such rad executables
Tyler: at the open source world will just flourish. There will be this ecosystem of open source
Tyler: things and then you can take it off the shelf and have your AI modify it to be exactly what
Tyler: you want and skin it and then you can share that. And I think that that is a more beautiful
Tyler: vision of what that could look like than being software as a service peasants on the feudal
Chris: estate of Salesforce.com or something.
Jackson: I still think we're far from that. There's a bridge between everyone having an agent
Jackson: and like customizing their software.
Jackson: And like today that is like long gone.
Jackson: I think people still need, normal people still need us or people that tailor,
Jackson: tailor their software and deliver it to them in a nice little box because they
Jackson: don't know what they want.
Jackson: They don't know that agents are super sexy and amazing.
Jackson: They don't know a lot that, that we happen to know.
Jackson: I don't know.
Jackson: Totally.
Jackson: But I showed a guy instinct and he's like, I'm going to fire my assistant.
Jackson: And I'm like, I'm sorry to hear that for, for that person, but happy for you.
Chris: Yeah, I love, but it's, you know, it's going to be all of us.
Chris: So that's cool.
Tyler: Uh, Jackson, can you have an instinct update?
Jackson: Yeah, I've got a huge instinct update actually.
Jackson: So in the past week, I got it.
Jackson: I got instinct to, I read quick, quick recap instincts, like a
Jackson: textable agent, and I got instinct to sign me up for a tennis
Jackson: tournament every weekend through the end of the, or not every
Jackson: weekend, every week through the end of the year, within six
Jackson: hours. And then I've gotten it to book rental cars, train
Jackson: transportation. And what is the other thing hotels, and I do all
Jackson: my cost comparisons and the WhatsApp. I trust it. I haven't even checked what it did. I just got
Jackson: some confirmation emails from six, which is a car rental company, a confirmation email from the
Jackson: train company. And I'm just letting it rip while I like drool on myself and watch you do.
Tyler: Did you say a lot of tennis? You're playing a tournament every week
Tyler: for the rest of the year. Yeah.
Jackson: Yeah. Well, I'm trying to get into some professional qualifying events and like
Jackson: the odds of me getting in are pretty low because it's like a chicken and the egg
Jackson: problem where you need a ranking to enter. So I'm like spreading myself, not then,
Jackson: or yeah, I guess then spreading myself wide for these.
Tyler: So are you trying to like, just to have a run in one tournament and that's what you need? Or
Tyler: Do you need to like do okay and all tournaments?
Jackson: Uh, I just want to shoot my 30 year old shot as my body degrades.
Jackson: Uh, I just want to see what can my 30 year old body, uh, perform.
Jackson: How can it do?
Jackson: So I'm just going to play with you.
Chris: You're the youngest person on the pod.
Chris: Okay.
Jackson: Yeah, sorry, guys.
Jackson: Keep it quiet, man.
Chris: Yeah.
Tyler: You're like, my 30 year old body is degrading because I'm playing like 20
Tyler: hours of Tennessee, semi-professionally. That is how you injure yourself when you're
Tyler: 30 years old. That's how you injure yourself when you're any years old.
Jackson: It used to be like your career ends in tennis at around 30, but no vacuum.
Tyler: Did instincts try to talk you out of this grueling schedule? Was it like Jackson,
Tyler: I am worried about your body. I think maybe you should look into some periodization and
Jackson: like, you know, take a rest week. So that's, that's a good question. Instinct never polices
Jackson: anything I do. Uh, so far. Well, actually, there was one identification thing where it was like,
Jackson: can you legally drive this car? And I was like, don't worry about it. I'll figure it out.
Jackson: Do you like it? Trust. Yeah. So that was the one thing it was like really adamant. And I'm like,
Jackson: Is the website asking you this? And it was like, no, but I don't want you to get there
Jackson: and be turned away. And I'm like, don't worry about it, dude. This is me.
Jackson: But yeah, so it's not like Claude or, or, um, open it out everywhere. It's like,
Jackson: it's like my daddy. It's more like my, my brother that is unemployed and does whatever I want.
Chris: Has it posted all of your transaction details to company Slack? Did you see the guy who
Chris: it did that to? No. I don't know. I don't know. Well, I think it was, I really, truly
Chris: think it was a skill issue, but he was like, yes, for some reason, Instinct posted my entire
Chris: banking transaction history to my company Slack. I'm like, how does that happen? I don't
Tyler: know.
Tyler: I mean, if you are connecting your personal instincts to your company Slack, you have
Tyler: a skill issue personally. And also your company has a skill issue of letting this random external
Tyler: AI connect to your company Slack and read and post to your entire company knowledge base.
Jackson: Jesus Christ. Maybe his instinct built a custom connector to connect itself to the Slack. And he
Jackson: was just a little too open kimono about it to stop. Very determined agent.
Jackson: They could do anything if they put their minds to it. So all that to say, it's amazing. And
Tyler: yeah, you're a big instinct guy now. You're a big instinct guy. How did it do the payments for all
Tyler: these transactions? You just give it your credit card and it just stores it in plain text on the
Jackson: instinct server and you just rock with that. I care so little about privacy. It adds it to a vault.
Jackson: And then every time I want to pay something, I have to approve.
Jackson: So I don't know how the vault works. I don't know anything. I just know that it's working.
Jackson: And I'm the ideal consumer, I think.
Chris: Is it like a ghost credit card? Or you have no idea. It just works.
Jackson: Well, I've entered all my credit card information.
Jackson: into this mall. It's like a link out to their website, to the instinct website. I input a bunch
Chris: of information. Okay. Yeah. So it is just doing it's like hard on file. Caught on file.
Tyler: Nice. But it's not instinct that charges you. It's like six charges you directly.
Jackson: Actually, I'm not, I don't really have it looked at your credit card.
Tyler: Like, dude, it thinks just bought itself an entire GPU farm and migrated its weights there
Chris: on your dime.
Jackson: It's not clawed.
Jackson: It's not going to like, yeah, buy itself more RAM so it can run even harder.
Jackson: Maybe it does.
Jackson: Maybe I'll update that one on the next, on the next week.
Jackson: Tyler, how's your, how's your gambling going?
Jackson: Are you whipping our bet?
Tyler: So I went through four different 15 minute segments.
Tyler: Unfortunately, I had a little bit of a roller coaster. I lost the first one. So I went from
Tyler: 25 to 10. And then I had two winners. So I went from 10 to like 50. And then I lost
Tyler: the last one. So I'm back down to 25. So I'm exactly where I started, which is basically
Tyler: what per per fortune is anyways. So the whole all or nothing experience I was promising
Tyler: the viewers was a lie.
Jackson: Technically you did better than the per per fortune that is down $2 on 100.
Chris: Which has done the worst type of nothing imaginable again, a slight loss.
Jackson: But it's work in progress. Tyler did do some vibe coding with his expert software engineering
Jackson: skills to update The Purple Fortune. We just didn't get a chance to test it beforehand,
Jackson: but next week we should be live with the most volatile gambling on the podcast you've ever seen.
Jackson: So please tune in next week for Tyler's mad creation and thank you very much. Have a good
Insert: weekend.